and the deep oceans are what we call "carbon sinks," because they trap and hold excess carbon from the atmosphere, and therefore help to delay global warming. Sometimes these carcasses also wash up on beaches and provide a meal to a number of predatory species on land. The 200 years of whaling was clearly detrimental and caused a reduction in the populations of whales between 60 to 90 percent. Clearly, the Save the Whales movement was instrumental in preventing commercial whaling from going on, but we need to revise this. We need to address the more modern, pressing problems that these whales face in our waters today. Amongst other things, we need to stop them from getting plowed down by container ships when they're in their feeding areas, and stop them from getting entangled in fishing nets as they float around in the ocean. We also need to learn to contextualize our conservation messages, so people really understand the true ecosystem value of these creatures. So, let's save the whales again, but this time, let's not just do it for their sake. Let's also do it for ours. Thank you. (Applause)
en las aguas profundas que llamamos "sumideros de carbono" porque atrapan y retienen el exceso de carbono de la atmósfera, por lo tanto ayudan a ralentizar el calentamiento global. A veces, estos cadáveres también terminan en las playas proporcionando alimento a algunas especies de depredadores terrestres. Los 200 años de caza de ballenas han sido claramente perjudiciales y han causado una disminución de la población de ballenas de un 60 % a un 90 %. Claramente, el movimiento "Salvemos a las ballenas" ha sido la mejor forma de evitar que continúe la caza comercial de ballenas pero tenemos que volver a esta campaña. Tenemos que abordar los problemas más modernos, más apremiantes a los cuales se enfrentan estas ballenas en nuestras aguas hoy. Entre otras cosas, tenemos que dejar de arrasarlas con buques portacontenedores cuando están en sus áreas de alimentación, o alejarlas de las redes de pesca en las que quedan enredadas mientras flotan en el océano. También tenemos que aprender a contextualizar nuestros mensajes conservacionistas para que la gente entienda realmente el verdadero valor de estas criaturas. Salvemos de nuevo a las ballenas, pero esta vez, no lo hagamos solo en beneficio de ellas. Hagámoslo también por nosotros. Gracias. (Aplausos)